<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>ResBaz Sydney 2023</title>
    <description>A conference promoting digital literacy and skill-sharing for researchers</description>
    <link>http://localhost:4000/resbaz2023syd/</link>
    <atom:link href="http://localhost:4000/resbaz2023syd/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
      <item>
        <title>Gale Digital Scholar Lab - Text and Data Mining - HASS</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;Think ResBaz is just for STEM? Think again! ResBaz is holding multiple
Humanities and Social Science events across the three days! Learn about &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.gale.com/intl/primary-sources/digital-scholar-lab&quot;&gt;Gale
Digital Scholar Lab&lt;/a&gt;, a new cloud-based text and data mining environment, which
combines open-source tools with Gale’s digital archive collections in an
integrated platform. This new platform seeks to combat two key barriers to
successfully taking on a Digital Humanities project, which can be summarised
as-&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Access to relevant data in a format optimised for analysis,&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Hosting, organising and sharing of large amounts of OCR and metadata.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Or explore the &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.atap.edu.au/&quot;&gt;Australian Text Analytics Platform (ATAP)&lt;/a&gt;, an ongoing national
project which provides web-enabled notebooks which allow researchers to use the
latest analytical tools to accelerate their work with unstructured text,
allowing automated analysis of conversations, semantic tagging, named entity
recognition and more.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Want to learn about NTROs? Come by and hear about case studies which include
research output from non-STEM projects which will explore different concepts of
what research data looks like, and how digital tools can be applied. There are
plenty of topics for those in the humanities. Come and join us at ResBaz to see
what’s right for you. &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.eventbrite.com.au/e/resbaz-sydney-2023-tickets-707597462057&quot;&gt;Register here!&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Mon, 18 Sep 2023 23:00:00 +1000</pubDate>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/resbaz2023syd/news/HASS</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/resbaz2023syd/news/HASS</guid>
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>High Performance Computing</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;Are you curious about high performance computing? What about Quantum Computers? Earthbytes or want to learn the basics of Linux? At ResBaz we have multiple events that cater to your HPC queries and curiosities.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So what is high performance computing? High performance computing is essentially the use of supercomputers and computer clusters to solve advanced computation problems. High performance computing involves integrating systems administration and parallel programming that combines digital electronics, computer architecture, system software, programming languages, algorithms and computational techniques.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Dietmar Müller will be introducing EarthByte, an eGeoscience collaboration between several Australian universities, internation centres of excellence and industry partners, which has a myriad of applications from providing boundary conditions for high-performance computing Earth evolution models to critical mineral exploration with end-users in over 190 countries.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Learn about Quantum Brilliance which seeks to change the capability of quantum computing. Quantum Brilliance computers creates an opportunity for mass deployment of huge clusters of quantum accelerators, which will be capable of addressing complex systems of systems such as molecular dynamics, leading to anticipated advances in battery technology, drug discovery and many more.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You can also get hands-on experience in Linux and high-performance computing, using the NCI Gadi HPC system. Each session touches on another aspect of high-performance computing. For more presentations please see our program &lt;a href=&quot;/resbaz2023syd/program/&quot;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Mon, 11 Sep 2023 23:00:00 +1000</pubDate>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/resbaz2023syd/news/HPC-2023</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/resbaz2023syd/news/HPC-2023</guid>
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>ResBaz 2023</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;You might have heard about it by word of mouth, through a poster or even an
email. But you’re not quite sure exactly what ResBaz is. Is it about Python?
Quantum computing? Wellbeing? Cheap food? Well, ResBaz is a three-day,
worldwide, low-cost festival that focuses on promoting digital literacy
emerging at the centre of modern research. It is organised by universities
across the globe and has been running since 2015 as a way for researchers from
different universities to share their knowledge and expertise.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Do you have trouble with Python? High performance computing piques your
interest? Or maybe your research is getting you down and you need to get tips
on how to manage stress? ResBaz touches on all of this offering keynotes, talks
and workshops for researchers at any level but especially Masters by Research
students, PhD students and early career researchers. Learn from experts in the
industry and improve your understanding of one of the myriad of offerings from
ResBaz.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Whilst RezBas is about learning and challenging yourself, it’s also about
building community. Research should not be siloed, but apart of an
ever-connecting network. ResBaz seeks to combat the loneliness that plagues the
academic community by offering face-to-face talks, workshops and  hacky hours
that encourage connections with people within the research community. Come and
join us for ResBaz 2023! We’re sure you’ll have fun and learn something new
too.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Thu, 07 Sep 2023 23:00:00 +1000</pubDate>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/resbaz2023syd/news/ResBaz-2023</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/resbaz2023syd/news/ResBaz-2023</guid>
      </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
